Finding Aid for Harriett Phillips papers, 1952-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Harriett Phillips papers 1952-1978
Phillips, Harriett
2 linear feet
85350 Aa 2
Michigan Democratic Party worker; political papers, scrapbooks, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Harriett Phillips (donor no. 6027 ) and came to the library in 1977.
The collection is open to research.
Harriett Phillips was born June 18, 1923 in Detroit, Michigan. She was a long-time worker in the Michigan Democratic Party, serving on the State Central Committee (beginning in 1954) and as vice chair (beginning in 1961). She was also chair of the party's legislative liaison sub-committee, and chair of the party's 18th congressional district committee.
Harriett Phillips was also involved in the opposition to state aid to parochial schools in the period of 1967-1971, serving as chair of the Committee to Advance Public Education and chair of the Council Against Parochiaid.
The collection consists of political papers (arranged chronologically), files relating to her opposition to state aid to parochial schools, photographs, and scrapbooks.
Subjects:
Church schools--Michigan--Finance.; Committee to Advance Public Education.; Council About Parochiaid.; Government aid to private schools--Michigan.; Democratic Party (Mich.).; Democratic Party (Mich.). State Central Committee.; Education--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Democratic Party (Mich.); Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Swainson, John Burley, 1925-; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-
Contributors:
Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Photographs.
- Political Papers
  (some of these materials were found loose in the scrapbooks)
  - 1950-1955 (Box 1)
  - 1956 (Box 1)
  - 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967 (Box 1)
  - 1968 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 1)
- Other Activities
  - Committee to Advance Public Education (CAPE) (Box 1)
  - Papers 1967-1970, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Council Against Parochiaid, 1978 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Photos of Phillips with political personages and as member of a group, 3 envelopes (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  (include clippings, correspondence, photographs, political documents, and memorabilia)
  - 1950s-1960s, 6 volumes (Box 2)